take a look at this little grid of
values which involve some positive
numbers on the left and some negative
numbers on the right which I'll color
with blue and red
respectively all in all this little
process basically detects wherever
there's variation in the pixel value As
you move from left to right and so it
gives you a kind of way to pick up on
all the vertical edges from your
image and similarly if we rotated that
grid around so that it varies As you
move from the top to the bottom this
will be picking up on all the horizontal
edges
which in the case of our little pie
creature image does result in some
pretty demonic
eyes this smaller grid by the way is
often called a kernel and the beauty
here is how just by choosing a different
kernel you can get different image
processing effects not just blurring
your Edge detection but also things like
sharpening for those of you who have
heard of a convolutional neural network
the idea there is to use data to figure
out what the kernels should be in the
first place as determined by whatever
the neural network wants to detect